Guide to the Records of the Research Institute for the Study of Man's (RISM) Medical and Social Anthropological Research in Bolivia RISM.RG.8
New York University Archives
- Series IV. Epidemiological Research Records, 1963-2003; 18.4 Linear Feet in 28 box binders, 17 manuscript boxes, 3 record cartons, and 2 half manuscript boxes
  - Subseries E. Epidemiological Study Documents, 1964-1965; 8 Linear Feet in 17 manuscript boxes and 1 half manuscript box
    - San Miguel, 1964-1965 (Box 207, Folder 1-114, Box 357, Folder 32-73, Box 358, Folder 1-20)
    - Villa Abecia, 1964-1965 (Box 208, Folder 1-56, Box 358, Folder 21-60, Box 359, Folder 1-54)
    - Coroico, 1964-1965 (Box 210, Folder 1-93, Box 360, Folder 1-85, Box 362, Folder 1-72, Box 363, Folder 1-8)
    - Sorata, 1964-1965 (Box 209, Folder 1-77, Box 359, Folder 55-62, Box 361, Folder 1-91)
    - La Paz, 1964-1965 (Box 363, Folder 9-12)
    - Peñas, 1964-1965 (Box 211, Folder 1-7)
    - Coroico School, 1964-1965 (Box 212, Folder 1-5)
    - Reyes School, 1964-1965 (Box 212, Folder 6-8)
    - Compi School, 1964-1965 (Box 212, Folder 9-10)
  - Subseries F. Blood Samples: Blood Typing Cards, 1964-1984; 3.2 Linear Feet in 19 box binders
    Subseries F consists of 2,192 blood typing cards placed in archival polypropylene binders. The cards in this series, housed to minimize movement and moisture retention, were used for blood typing and indexed by the Member of the Household Number.
    Conditions Governing Access
    Repository permission is required for access to material in Subseries IV. F. Please contact New York University Archives, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
    - Compi 1-1 to 64-1, undated (Box 180)
    - Compi 64-2 to 98-5, undated (Box 181)
    - Compi 99-1 to 160-1, undated (Box 182)
    - Coroico 1-1 to 66-1, undated (Box 183)
    - Coroico 66-2 to 133-2, undated (Box 184)
    - Coroico 134-1 to 197-2, undated (Box 185)
    - Coroico 197-3 to 253-1, undated (Box 186)
    - Coroico 253-2 to 270-12, undated (Box 187)
    - Reyes 1-1 to 40-2, undated (Box 188)
    - Reyes 41-1 to 83-1, undated (Box 189)
    - Reyes 83-3 to 127-3, undated (Box 190)
    - Reyes 127-4 to 174-1, undated (Box 191)
    - Reyes 175-1 to 211-1, undated (Box 192)
    - San Miguel 1-1 to 80-1, undated (Box 193)
    - San Miguel 81-1 to 177-2, undated (Box 194)
    - Sorata 2-1 to 62-2, undated (Box 195)
    - Sorata 63-1 to 116-4, undated (Box 196)
    - Sorata 116-5 to 170-1, undated (Box 197)
    - Sorata 170-2 to 177-2, undated (Box 198)
- Series V. Ethnographic Research Records, 1964-1989; 20.3 Linear Feet in 62 box binders and 4 manuscript boxes
  This series has been arranged into six subseries, as follows:
  Subseries A. Changing Rural Society Material
  Subseries B. Community Study Outline (CSO)/ Bosquejo para el estudio de las Communidades
  Subseries C. Field Notes / Notas de Campo
  Subseries D. Codes
  Subseries E. Community Census/ Censo de la Comunidad
  Subseries F. Household Structure Diagram/Bosquejo de Casa
  Scope and Contents note
  The materials in this series relate to the ethnographic study undertaken between 1964 and 1967. The final report was published in 1969 as Changing Rural Bolivia. The report was republished in 1971 by Oxford University Press as Changing Rural Society. The materials have been divided into five subseries.
  - Subseries A. Changing Rural Society Material, 1964-1989; 1.3 Linear Feet in 3 manuscript boxes
    This subseries contains a published version of the report from 1969, drafts and correspondence regarding the republishing, and correspondence and curricula vitae for people applying/selected to work on the Bolivia project as well as other projects in the 1970s and 1980s.
    - Changing Rural Bolivia -- Drafts and Correspondence, 1964-1989 (Box 213, Folder 1-6, Box 347, Folder 2-14, Box 364, Folder 1-12, Box 380, Folder 1-26)
  - Subseries B. Community Study Outline (CSO)/ Bosquejo para el estudio de las Communidades, 1964; 0.5 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box
    This subseries consists of the Community Study Outline (CSO)/Bosquejo para el estudio de las communidades. The CSO is an outline that was used to standardize and index the information recorded in the field notes generated by each anthropologist. The one exception is Compi, where the anthropologists were already present in the community conducting their own research. These forms document the information in the card files in Subseries C. Field Notes / Notas de Campo filed under specific numbers documenting geographic environment, population demographics, history and development, institutional systems, the sociopolitical system, community and private health, and the Peace Corps program.
    - Community Study Outline, 1964 (Box 347, Folder 1)
  - Subseries C. Field Notes / Notas de Campo, 1964-1967; 18.5 Linear Feet in 62 box binders
    This subseries consists of 14,000 pages and 30 bound volumes of field notes, organized by community and fieldworker. The field notes were processed by a team of data coders and analysts, who produced the CSO Indexed Field Notes Cards and the Biographical Index. The field notes are organized by community and then by name of fieldworker.
    The field notes document the experiences of the fieldworkers, including descriptions of the villages in which they worked, people they met and spoke with through the course of their work, and drawings of buildings and other parts of the villages. The notes are in English and Spanish. Descriptions of medicinal plants in villages and what each can be used for; descriptions of relationships between villagers; work done by villagers; what women buy from markets, how much, and how often; health of the field workers; cattle driving routes; religious orders in the villages and religious events; fiestas in each village and the significances and different aspects (social and religious) of each. Two boxes contain court judgments in Compi and Villa Abecia.
    - Reconnaissance, 1964 (Box 214)
    - Compi, 1964-1965 (Box 215, Box 216)
    - Coroico -- Alfredo Antezana G. (AAG), 1964-1965 (Box 217)
    - Coroico -- Felix Mangudo C. (FMC), 1964-1965 (Box 219, Box 218, Box 220)
    - Coroico -- Eloy A Robalino S. (EARS), 1964-1965 (Box 379, Box 221, Box 222, Box 223, Box 224)
    - Coroico -- Katherine J. Barnes (KJB), 1965 (Box 225, Box 226, Box 227)
    - Coroico -- Dwight B. Heath (DBH), 1964-1965 (Box 228, Box 229, Box 230)
    - Coroico -- Roger Newman (Mururata), 1965 (Box 231)
    - Reyes -- Multiple Fieldworkers, 1964-1965 (Box 232)
    - Reyes -- Gerardo Pereira R. (GPR), 1965 (Box 233)
    - Reyes -- Said Madde J. (SMJ), 1964-1965 (Box 234, Box 235)
    - Reyes -- Gwen Novick (GN), 1965 (Box 236)
    - Reyes -- Victor C. Novick (VCN), 1964-1965 (Box 237, Box 238, Box 239)
    - San Miguel -- Lauren C. Klein (LCK), 1965 (Box 240)
    - San Miguel -- Solomon Miller (SM), 1966-1967 (Box 241)
    - Sorata -- Multiple Fieldworkers, 1965 (Box 242)
    - Sorata -- KatherineJ. Barnes (KJB), 1966 (Box 243, Box 244)
    - Sorata -- Beverly J. Holcombe (BJH), 1965-1966 (Box 245, Box 246, Box 247)
    - Sorata -- Paz Mejia M. (PMM), 1966 (Box 248, Box 249, Box 376, Box 369)
    - Sorata -- Jaime Vilela (JVS), 1966 (Box 250, Box 251, Box 252)
    - Sorata -- Eloy A. Robalino S. (EARS), 1964-1965 (Box 253, Box 254, Box 370, Box 371)
    - Sorata -- Fernando Varela B. (FVB), 1966 (Box 255)
    - Villa Abecia -- Roso Avila B. (RAB), 1966 (Box 256, Box 372)
    - Villa Abecia -- Carlos Avila B. (CAB), 1965-1966 (Box 257, Box 258)
    - Villa Abecia -- Victor C. Novick (VCN), 1965-1966 (Box 259, Box 261, Box 373)
    - VCN (1 - 250) -- copy, 1965 (Box 260)
    - Villa Abecia -- Court Judgements, 1966 (Box 261)
    - VCN (251 - 497) -- copy, 1966 (Box 262)
    - Villa Abecia -- Katherine J. Barnes (KJB), 1965-1966 (Box 263, Box 264)
    - Villa Abecia: Said Madde J. (SMJ), 1965-1966 (Box 265, Box 266, Box 374, Box 375)
  - Subseries D. Codes, 1967-1972; 0.5 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box
    - Codes, 1967-1972 (Box 338, Folder 1-8)
- Series VI. Surveys and Questionnaires, 1965-1966; 40 Linear Feet in 3 manuscript boxes, 2 half manuscript boxes, and 35 record cartons
  The materials in this series have been divided into two subseries, Subseries A. Attitudinal Questionnaire /Cedula de Creencias and Subseries B. Household Social Survey / Encuesta sobre la Comunidad.
  This series contains questionnaires and surveys conducted as part of the ethnographic research study.
  - Subseries A. Attitudinal Questionnaire / Cedula de Creencias, 1965-1966; 2.8 Linear Feet in 2 record cartons, 1 manuscript box, and 1 half manuscript box
    This subseries. contains 229 Attitudinal Questionnaires/Cedulas de Creencias. These questionnaires are organized by community and include the names of persons who were interviewed, mainly teenagers to middle aged men. These names may also appear in the Biographical Index in Subseries III. A. The questionnaires include questions on family, life, work, aspirations, and broad social and cultural attitudes. Specific topics include looking for work, repairing water sources, and raising children. Hypothetical situations are offered on each topic, followed by a series of questions based on these topics.
    - Coroico, 1965 (Box 267, Folder 1-20, Box 269, Folder 7-14)
    - Reyes, 1965 (Box 268, Folder 1-10, Box 365, Folder 1-5)
    - Sorata, 1966 (Box 269, Folder 1-6)
  - Subseries B. Household Social Survey / Encuesta Sobre la Comunidad, 1966; 36.8 Linear Feet in 33 record cartons, 2 manuscript boxes, and 1 half manuscript box
    This subseries contains 1,094 Household Social Surveys/Encuestas sobre la Communidad. These surveys have not been fully analyzed or indexed with other materials in the collection. Some materials were processed and analyzed by Jonathan L. Kelley and Herbert S. Klein for their study Revolution and the Rebirth of Inequality, published in 1981. The surveys consist of open ended questions about family life, household set up (including water and toilet facilities), family size, and opinions about community, education, work, and membership in labor unions.
    - Compi, 1966 (Box 270, Folder 1-15, Box 271, Folder 1-16)
    - Coroico, 1966 (Box 273, Folder 1-6, Box 274, Folder 1-16, Box 275, Box 276, Folder 1-14, Box 277, Folder 1-11, Box 278, Folder 1-10)
    - Reyes, 1966 (Box 279, Folder 1-11, Box 280, Folder 1-10, Box 281, Folder 1-9, Box 282, Folder 1-16, Box 283, Folder 1-17, Box 284, Box 285, Box 286, Box 287, Box 366, Folder 1-3, Box 288, Box 289)
    - San Miguel, 1966 (Box 290, Folder 1-13, Box 291, Folder 1-16, Box 292, Box 366, Folder 5-7, Box 367, Folder 1-2)
    - Sorata, 1966 (Box 293, Folder 1-15, Box 294, Folder 1-17, Box 295, Folder 1-16, Box 296, Box 297, Box 298, Box 299, Box 288, Folder 11-16, Box 366, Folder 4, Box 367, Folder 3-7, Box 377, Folder 1-2)
    - Capilaya, 1966 (Box 300, Folder 1-16, Box 301, Folder 1-15)
    - Villa Abecia, 1966 (Box 289, Folder 12-16, Box 302, Folder 1-15, Box 303)
- Series VII. Unpublished Manuscripts, 1964-1970; 2 Linear Feet in 4 manuscript boxes
  This series has been arranged in two subseries: Subseries A. Student Papers and Subseries B. Conference and Working Papers.
  The materials in this series have been arranged alphabetically by author's name. This series has been organized into two subseries.
  - Subseries A. Student Papers, 1965-1967; 1 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes
    Scope and Content
    The materials in this subseries consist of student papers prepared by students from Columbia University and the University of Kentucky. Students developed these papers during summer fieldwork studies conducted by Dr. Lambros Comitas, Assistant Director of the Research Institute for the Study of Man.
    Please be aware that FERPA guidelines may prevent access to student materials in the absence of a signed release form.
    - Local Government in Bolivia: Public Administration and Popular Participation, Adrianne Aron, undated (Box 306, Folder 1)
    - Realities of Bolivian Education, Bambi Bernhard, 1966 (Box 306, Folder 2)
    - Agrarian Reform and Migration Migration (Section I - The Community Level) Hans C. Buechler, undated (Box 306, Folder 3)
    - Agrarian Reform and Migration (Section II. The Family Level) Hans C. Buechler, undated (Box 306, Folder 4)
    - Tentative Outline of Master's Thesis Essay and Draft Essay: A Study of Child Development in a Bolivian Altiplano Community, Judith-Maria Buechler, undated (Box 306, Folder 5)
    - A Study of Child Development on the Bolivian Altiplano [Chapter 1 missing], Judith-Maria Buechler, undated (Box 306, Folder 6)
    - A Study of Child Development on the Bolivian Altiplano [pp. 1 - 70], Judith-Maria Buechler, undated (Box 306, Folder 7)
    - A Study of Child Development on the Bolivian Altiplano [pp. 71 - 161], Judith-Maria Buechler, undated (Box 306, Folder 8)
    - Coroico, Bolivia, Rachel Eubank, 1966 (Box 306, Folder 9)
    - The Development of Bolivian Rural Education, 1900 - 1969, John Francis Hohenstein, 1970 (Box 307, Folder 1)
    - A Community Health Study of Reyes, Bolivia, David Lawrence, 1967 (Box 307, Folder 2)
    - Draft essay: Aymara Folkmedicine: Folk Medicine in Huatajata, Bolivia, William J. Mitchell, undated (Box 307, Folder 3)
    - Folk Medicine in Huatajata, Bolivia, William J. Mitchell, 1967 (Box 307, Folder 4)
    - Inter-Group Relations in Highland Bolivia, Roger C. Newman, 1965 (Box 307, Folder 5)
    - Land Reform in Bolivia's Yungas, Roger C. Newman, undated (Box 307, Folder 6)
    - Local Health Study of Villa Abecia, Bolivia, Patterned After WHO Recommendations for Community Study, Edwin G. Nighbert, 1965 (Box 307, Folder 7)
    - Analysis of Infant Feeding Practices in Sorata, Bolivia, Susan Scrimshaw, 1966 (Box 307, Folder 8)
    - Outline of Local Health Study of Compi, Bolivia, Paul W. Wright, 1965 (Box 307, Folder 9)
  - Subseries B. Conference and Working Papers, 1966-1970; 2 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes
    The materials in this subseries consist of conference papers organized by field directors in Bolivia.
    - The United States and the Bolivian Revolution (1952 - 1964), Cole Blasier, undated (Box 308, Folder 1)
    - Processes of Bolivian Syndicalism: A Reinterpretation of the Relationship Between Social Behavior and Institutions, Hans Buechler, 1970 (Box 308, Folder 2)
    - The Effect of the Bolivian Land Reform Upon Human Resources in the Lake Titicaca Region, Melvin Burke, undated (Box 308, Folder 3)
    - The Bolivian Aymara and Social Change: A Reevaluation of the "Culture Broker" Concept, Hans Christian and Judith-Maria Buechler, 1969 (Box 308, Folder 4)
    - Revolution and the Agrarian Sector, William E. Carter, undated (Box 308, Folder 5)
    - Bolivia in Time of Revolution, Holy Week 1952, Carter Goodrich, undated (Box 308, Folder 6)
    - Biculturalism: The Aymara Case, John M. Hickman, 1968 (Box 308, Folder 7)
    - Prelude to the Revolution, Herbert S. Klein, undated (Box 308, Folder 8)
    - Continuity and Discontinuity in Peasant Economics in the Province of Nor Yungas, Bolivia, Madeline Barbara Leons and William Leons, undated (Box 308, Folder 9)
    - The Bolivian Novel, The Chaco War, and the Revolution, Murdo J. Macleod, undated (Box 308, Folder 10)
    - Bolivia's MNR: A Study of a National Popular Movement in Latin America, James M. Malloy, 1968 (Box 308, Folder 11)
    - Revolutionary Politics in Bolivia, James M. Malloy, 1969 (Box 308, Folder 12)
    - On Analyzing the Sociometric Information in the Bolivia Project Questionnaire, Frank Many [?], 1966 (Box 308, Folder 13)
    - Social Change and National Integration in Bolivia, William J. McEwen, undated (Box 308, Folder 14)
    - Theory and Methodology of the RISM Bolivia Project, William J. McEwen, undated (Box 309, Folder 1)
    - Education in Bolivia, Robert G. Myers, 1969 (Box 309, Folder 2)
    - Changing Bases of Social Stratification in a Bolivian Community, Blanca Muratorio, 1966 (Box 309, Folder 3)
    - Revolutionary Change in a Bolivian Hacienda Town, Victor Novick, 1966 (Box 309, Folder 4)
    - Too Many Indians, Not Enough Chiefs: Leadership Crisis in a Bolivian Hacienda Town, Victor Novick, undated (Box 309, Folder 5)
    - San Carlos -- Camba Town, Allyn MacLean Stearman, 1971 (Box 309, Folder 6)
    - Las Realidades de la Educacion Primaria En Bolivia, Senior Alberto Tardio, 1967 (Box 309, Folder 7)
    - Bolivia: The Economic Transformtion, Richard S. Thorn, 1969 (Box 309, Folder 8)
    - Bolivia's Public Financial Policy and Foreign Trade Since 1952, James W. Wilkie, 1969 (Box 309, Folder 9)
    - Bolivia in the 1970s: What Kind of Revolution?, Bernard M. Wood, undated (Box 309, Folder 10)
    - La Organizacion Nuclear En Bolivia, Carlos A. Vildozo, undated (Box 309, Folder 11)
    - Los Estudiantes Y La Universidad "Estudio de Actitudes" (Investi-gacion Preliminar), Centro De Investigation, Instituto Bolivano De Estudios Y Accion Social (I.B.E.A.S), 1966 (Box 309, Folder 12)
    - Notes on Bolivian study areas, undated (Box 309, Folder 13-14)
    - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 309, Folder 15)
- Series VIII. Community and Regional Maps, 1964-2000; 0.1 Linear Feet in 1 flat file folder
  This series consists of 15 maps, arranged chronologically. Most of the maps in this series were hand drawn and provide details of the communities being studied. The maps were also used for planting purposes and for building.
  - Plano General De La Comunidad "Tauca" Provinicia Omasuyos Canton Stgo De Huata, Feb 1957 (Flat-file-folder 1)
  - Plano General De La Comunidad "Tauca" Provinicia Omasuyos Canton Stgo De Huata, Feb 1957 (Flat-file-folder 1)
  - Plano Parcelario y Replanteo de La Propiedad, Compi, Apr 1958 (Flat-file-folder 1)
  - Plano Parcelario y Replanteo de La Comunidad Capilaya, undated (Flat-file-folder 1)
  - Plano Parcial De La Hacienda "Compi", undated (Flat-file-folder 1)
  - Plano Parcial De La Hacienda "Compi", Aug 1964 (Flat-file-folder 1)
  - Plano Parcelario De "Compi" Amasi, Oct 1965? (Flat-file-folder 1)
  - Plano Parcelario De "Compi", undated (Flat-file-folder 1)
  - Plano Parcelario De Capilaya, undated (Flat-file-folder 1)
  - Plano General De Sorata, undated (Flat-file-folder 1)
  - Map of Communidad Llamacachi, undated (Flat-file-folder 1)
  - Map of Llamacachi, undated (Flat-file-folder 1)
  - Map of Villa Abecia, undated (Flat-file-folder 1)
  - Map of Coroico, undated (Flat-file-folder 1)
  - "Bolivia Project, 1964-1967", poster presentation, undated (Flat-file-folder 1)
- Series IX. Photographs, 1964-1968; 0.5 Linear Feet in 2 box binders
  This series consists of photographs and contact sheets depicting urban and rural landscapes, indigenous costumes, celebrations and festivals, musicians, market scenes, religious ceremonies, and interaction between the Bolivian population and members of the RISM epidemiology team. The photographs are arranged by content of the photographs, including men, women, work, politics, type of landscape, and festivals. Box 311 contains lists of photographs taken by Dwight B. Heath. Photographers include Kay Barnes and Victor Novick in Villa Abecia, William McEwen in Sorota, Herbert Klein in San Miguel, K. Barnes and Dwight B. Heath in Coroico, Victor Novick in Reyes, and Lambros Comitas and Vera D. Rubin in multiple locations.
  The photographs are arranged by content of the photographs, including men, women, work, politics, type of landscape, and festivals.
  - Photographs, 1964-1968 (Box 310, Box 311)
- Series X. Audiovisual Materials, 1969; 2 Linear Feet in 2 record cartons
  Partly as a result of the RISM Bolivia Project (1964-1967), the United States Office of Education in 1968 and 1969 sponsored a study of rural education in Argentina, Bolivia, and Jamaica. The principal investigator of this study was Lambros Comitas, then Professor of Anthropology and Education at Teachers College, Columbia University, and Associate Director of the Research Institute for the Study of Man.
  The Bolivia CV Recordings, an integral part of this comparative study, were taped by Lambros Comitas in 1969 using a Sony Videocorder and CV reel-to-reel videotape for helican scan video recorders.
  - The Living, undated; cuid272 (Box 314, 16mm film reels 1)
  - 16 mm film -- "Fable test" (Copy 1), undated; cuid273 (Box 314, Item 2)
  - Compi School, Bolivia A & B [Master], 1969; cuid274 (Box 314, Item 3)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Original Format: 3/4" U-Matic
    Duration: 47 Minutes
  - Bolivia C & D [Master], 1969; cuid275 (Box 314, Item 4)
    Original format: 3/4" U-Matic
  - Bolivia E & F [Master], 1969; cuid276 (Box 314, Item 4)
    Duration 47 Minutes
  - Bolivia G & H [Master], 1969; cuid277 (Box 314, Item 6)
  - Bolivia J & K [Master], 1969; cuid278 (Box 314, Item 7)
  - Bolivia L & M [Master], 1969; cuid279 (Box 314, Item 8)
  - Data tapes related to the epidemiological study (9), undated; cuid280 (Box 378)
  - Bolivia Part I Filmstrip, undated; cuid281 (Box 314, Item 2)
    Original format: 35mm filmstrip
  - Bolivia Part II Filmstrip, undated; cuid442 (Box 314)
  - Bolivia Part III Filmstrip, undated; cuid444 (Box 314)
  - Bolivia Part IV Filmstrip, undated; cuid446 (Box 314)
  - "Bolivia" - U.S. Productions Story 1 & Story 2 [1/4" Audio], undated; cuid439 (Box 314)
    Original format: 1/4" open reel audio
  - "Bolivia" - U.S. Productions Story 3 & Story 4 [1/4" Audio], undated; cuid440 (Box 314)
  - "Bolivia" - U.S. Productions Story 3 & Story 4 [Audiocassette Copy 1], undated; cuid282 (Box 314, Item 3)
    Format:
    Audiocassette
  - DAT tape labeled "Bolivia, RISM U.S. Productions", undated; cuid283 (Box 314, Item 4)
    Duration: 18 minutes.
  - Scripts related to RISM U.S. Productions films Lake Titicaca, A Land Conquered, and The Revolution, undated; cuid429 (Box 312, Folder 13)
  - RISM Bolivia Project, undated (Box 382)
- Series XI. Exhibition Material, 1997; 1.8 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box, 1 record carton, and 1 flat box
  - Promotional materials, 1997 (Box 313, Folder 22)
  - Exhibition poster: RISM Bolivia Project, 1964-1967, undated (Box 318, Item 1)
  - Exhibition poster: Bolivia: RISM Bolivia Project Study Communities, undated (Box 318, Item 2)
  - Project poster, rolled
  - RISM Bolivia Project text panels, undated (Box 368, Folder 1-6)
- Series XII. Reports from RISM to the Peace Corps, Partial Reports Related to the RISM Bolivia Project, 1964-1967; 1 Linear Feet in 1 record carton
  - Public Health Research in Bolivia, 1964 (Box 272, Folder 1)
  - A Study of Child Development in the Bolivian Altiplano, undated (Box 272, Folder 2)
  - Agrarian Reform & Migration on the Bolivian Altiplano, 1966 (Box 272, Folder 3)
  - Distribution List: A.A.A. Bolivia Papers, undated (Box 272, Folder 4)
  - Excerpt from untitled manuscript: "Section 1: The Community, The Geography." (Box 272, Folder 5)
  - Community Health Studies, undated (Box 272, Folder 6)
  - Comitas: Education and Social Stratification in Contemporary Bolivia, undated (Box 272, Folder 7)
  - Huatajata, General Observations (excerpt from manuscript), undated (Box 272, Folder 8)
  - Health, undated (Box 272, Folder 9)
  - Madeline, Barbara Leons: Land Reform in the Bolivian Yungas., undated (Box 272, Folder 10)
  - McEwan, undated (Box 272, Folder 11)
  - Muratorio, undated (Box 272, Folder 12)
  - Muratorio, Social, and Participation of the non-Yungan Campesinos: English and Spanish, undated (Box 272, Folder 13)
  - Aron, undated (Box 272, Folder 14)
  - Victor Novick: Too Many Indians, Not Enough Chiefs: Leadership Crisis in a Bolivian Hacienda Town., undated (Box 272, Folder 15)
  - Novick, undated (Box 272, Folder 16)
  - Background and Proposal for Field Work, Summer 1965, by Susan Sorinshaw (Box 272, Folder 17)
  - Maru Sera Sample: Total Epidemiological Sample., undated (Box 272, Folder 18)